www.linkedin.com/in/vasilijesimonovic



Vasilije Simonović

Previously a professional chess player, I am very good at solving logical and technical problems. I have working experience with Python, C#, SQL and MATLAB. As a part of my Master's degree, I have participated and developed several projects using Machine learning and Deep learning methods in Python.

EXPERIENCE

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

IT ADMINISTRATOR, IM MATIJEVIC

- Job consists of: supervision, administration, maintenance of information system, software system.
- LAN and VPN administration of business apps, support for system users in solving technical problems with hardware and software, locally and remote.
- Administration of MS SQL, MS office and other softwares, antiviruses, backup, restore and so on.
- In this company there are more than 160 stores and offices where I do supervision, administration and maintenance.

DECEMBER 2021 – APRIL 2022

DEEP LEARNING INTERN, ZUMMIT INFOLABS

- Worked on a team in two Deep Learning projects.
- Participated in researching, processing data, creation of the model (CNN) and testing the model
- Worked on a project on crop yield based on satellite images.
- Supported a project about recognizing diseases based on x-ray photos.
- Participated in daily status update calls where teams reported out current progress and project updates.
- Take part in the development of innovative CV solutions
- Analyze data used for training and testing.
- Train CV models and analyze their performance and limitations.
- Develop algorithms using machine learning, deep learning, image processing and computer vision.

MONTH 2018 – MONTH 2020 CONSULTANT, TECHPRO

- Helped with SQL databases and other backend tasks related to website development.
- Created a relational model from an Er model in SQL for a website which made TechPro.
- For a project, I filled the cells in an Excel table with Pandas in Python.
- Made an SQL guery which automatically put user data in a database.

JULY 2018 – SEPTEMBER 2018 LOFT MANAGER, EPW

- Managed the daily duties for a small team in the Netherlands for one of the most famous auction houses for racing pigeons.
- Oversaw the diets and nutrition for our team's pigeons so they could be in the most optimal shape for auctions.
- Doubled company profits after a very successful auction in which we sold pigeons that we raised.

EDUCATION

FEBRUARY 2022

MSC APPLIED MATHEMATICS -DATA SCIENCE, FACULTY OF SCIENCE, NOVI

SAD MASTER'S THESIS IN PROGRESS

Relevant Coursework:

Large Scale Data Mining, Programing for Data Science, Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition, Big Data in Medicine and Biology, Network science, Databases, Introduction to Image Processing, Graph Theory, Numerical Linear Algebra, Statistics Theory for Machine Learning and Signal Processing

OCTOBER 2014

B.S. APPLIED MATHEMATICS – FINANCIAL MATHEMATICS, FACULTY OF SCIENCE, NOVI SAD

SKILLS

- Python
- LinkedIn Badge Machine Learning
- LinkedIn Courses Python Data Analysis, Learning Django
- SQL
- Excel
- English
- Spanish (A2) Basic Proficiency

ACTIVITIES

Aside from the professional experience listed above, I have also completed freelance projects solving mathematics problems and tasks. I worked in Python and Excel on big data sets using pivot tables and other advanced analysis techniques. Some other projects I have in progress include: a pedigree program using Python Kivy, a python game "Rushing Bumblebee" for every platform (Mac, Windows, Android), creating a tractor navigation system that will speed up and improve agricultural production. Related to EPW position, later I made the CV project that I am most proud of: "Classification of racing pigeons based on pigeon eyes". The whole project was made in Python. For creation of the model, I used CNN with framework TensorFlow. This model can determine whether the pigeon is good or not and that can drastically change its value at auctions.